## Aye Thandar Swe

Business Data Analyst and Reporting Manager +9509662845011 / 09402540369 <u>ayethandarswe23@gmail.com</u> Kamayut Tsp, Yangon, Myanmar.

Dear Mr / Mrs / Miss,

If your organization is currently in need of a management professional with a record of achieving top performance, leading highly skilled teams, I am really searching for new opportunities that are beneficial for me. Therefore, I would like to present my resume and qualifications for your review.

Throughout my career in operations leadership positions as a specialist of Business Data Analyst and Reporting by Microsoft I have been at the Operation Department with Heads and Managers of regional wise and branches wise within challenging and complex environments. I have built team improvement through high quality and I have been able to adapt to the changing field.

Highlights from my experience include the development and implementation of multiple managers over a 7-year period.

My resume will provide additional details regarding my background and qualifications. I would welcome the opportunity for a personal interview so that we could discuss your organization and I have enclosed my resume for your review.

Thank you for your time and consideration.

Sincerely,

Aye Thandar Swe

Enclosure: Resume

## Resume

#### **SUMMARY**

Analyze operation planning and researching for Business Development, branch performance report daily, weekly and yearly period report, checking Daily report, attending management meeting, collect raw data from Manager and organize & analyze business data by Excel, Power Query, BI, DAX, Oracle SQL, Python and report to Chiefs and Heads of Department and presentation by monthly and yearly,

#### HIGHLIGHT HARD SKILLS

- Data Analysis / Business analysis
- Business Development / Research
- Proficient in Microsoft Office including Excel, Word and PowerPoint -

Preparing PowerPoint / Presentation

- Power bi / query / DAX / Power Automate / SQL/ Python
- Computer and internet Skills
- Able to Operate Under Pressure
- Ad hoc
- Creativity
- Decision Making

#### HIGHLIGHT SOFT SKILLS

- Teamwork
- GoodCommunication
- Problem solving
- Self-Motivation
- Time Management
- Responsible and Flexible
- Adaptable (Work in changing environment)

#### WORKING EXPERIENCE

#### Early Dawn Microfinance Company Ltd (Yangon)

#### Business Data Analyst, June 22 to now

- Analyze the business operational, financial data and the other performance related data using statistical techniques and generating requested reports.
- Provide analytical support, business data analysts to comprehend the business and information needs of the organization.
- Collaborate with other departmental managers to understand their business needs, formulate and complete end-to-end analysis that includes data gathering, data cleaning, data enrichment and build dashboards/reports to management.
- Working alongside teams within the business or the management team to establish business needs.
- Identifying patterns and trends in data sets.

- Managing and designing the reporting environment, including data sources, security, and metadata.
- Inform and report to MIS department with the evidence if any of the errors are detected in any customized operation report generated by MIS.
- Supporting the data warehouse in identifying and revising reporting requirements.
- Supporting initiatives for data integrity and normalization.
- Troubleshooting the reporting database environment and reports.
- Evaluating changes and updates to source production systems.
- Locate and define new process improvement opportunities.
- Training end-users on new reports and dashboards.
- Prepare presentations on Business analysis data based on requirements.
- Perform other tasks linked to the role and responsibilities as assigned by the supervisor.

# Hayman Capital Microfinance Company Ltd (Yangon) Analyst and Reporting Specialist Manager, December 2016 to June 22 (6 years)

Overall Responsibility: Responsible for

- Consolidate and analyze Operation data (budgets, outreach, branch financial performance, etc.) taking into account company's goals and financial standing
- Assemble and summarize data to structured sophisticated reports on company performance.
- Conduct business studies on past, future and comparative performance and develop forecast models.
- Identify trends, advise companies and recommend actions based on sound analysis.

#### Key Areas of Accountabilities

- Central Credit Committee Meeting, Asset and Liabilities committee Meeting, Robust reporting system Meeting and Branch Manager Meeting, organizing venues and taking minutes
- Creating PowerPoint Presentations for Management Board Meeting (Higher Level) Assistant Chief of Operation Officer and Head of Operation Department with the preparation of presentations.
- Creating yearly operating budget targets and comparing with previous months and collaborating data of branches and reporting to the COO.
- Creating yearly, monthly and daily branch performance and reporting to COO and higher level. Create outstanding records and report to HOD.
- In time organize the necessary documents, facilitate reports, and analyze operations under the supervision of COO and HOD.

## Serge Pun and Associates Project Management Services Ltd (Yangon) Administrator, September 2015 to December 2016 (1year and 3 months)

Overall Responsibility: Responsible for

- Provide dedicated, administrative and project support to team
- Organize the necessary team members and documents
- Facilitate, report and analyze projects under the supervision of a Sr. Project Manager

#### Key Areas of Accountabilities

- Coordinating meetings, organizing venues and taking minutes
- Updating the project calendar and tracking projects
- Creating PowerPoint Presentations
- Assist of Sr. Project Manager with the preparation of presentations
- Follow up on outstanding invoices and report back to Sr. PM

## **International Beverages Trading Company Ltd**

## Data Controller, September 2009 to September 2015 (6 years)

Overall Responsibility: Responsible for

- Sales record and data control
- Branch report generation
- Daily/monthly/yearly sales by channel by branch
- Daily/monthly/yearly account receivable and credit control Coordinate with sales and collection team

#### Key Areas of Accountabilities

- In time report and support to Branch level and National Level

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Business Administration (B.B.A)**

Meikhtila University of Economics, Myanmar January. 2005 to September. 2008

#### **Diploma in Business Law (D.B.L)**

University of Mandalay, Myanmar December. 2013 to September. 2014

#### **Diploma in Research Studies (DRS)**

Yangon Economics University

**Single Subject Diploma in Business Management and Administration**, (ICM).

### **QUALIFICATION**

- Certificate of Strategic Management (Strategy First Institute)
- Certificate of Business Management and Administration (Strategy First

Institute) - Certificate of Commerce in Ministry of Cooperative, Myanmar

- Certificate of Human Resource Management in Forber Academic Accountancy and Management Education (F.A.M.E)
- Completed a Certificate of English 4 skills in Yangon University of Foreign Language (YUFL)
- Completed Certificate of Advanced Microsoft Office
- Completed a Corporate Intellectual Development Workshop in "Team Building"

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of birth: 18<sup>th</sup> of February 1990

Marital Status : Single Nationality : Myanmar

Language: English / Burmese NIRC No: 9/MaHaNa(N) 015465

Available Period: 1 Month

Salary: Nego